{
    "id": "Politica_80",
    "claim": "Mandela never forgot those who treated him well. He always remained faithful to his jailer, Christo Brand, an individual who once was out of prison had no practical use for him, and to his son Riaan, whom he held in prison when he was a baby. Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend, told me that in prison he always called him “Mr. Brand” while he called him simply “Nelson”. This custom never changed, not even when Mandela came to the presidency and Brand phoned him to congratulate him. Mandela had given him his house number, a detail that Brand had with the same naturalness that when he mentioned that they met again in Amsterdam in 2002: “He introduced me to the Queen of Holland and I helped him climb the stairs”. Mandela invited Brand to celebrate his 80th birthday at the presidential residence in Pretoria in 1998, an event in which he also announced the marriage to his third wife, the woman with whom he would finally discover lasting happiness, Graça Machel, widow of whom he was President of Mozambique, Samora Machel, and former Minister of Education in his Government. Mandela organized Brand's trip from Cape Town. It was the first time in his life that he got on a plane. Seven years later it would be Mandela who would fly to his city to visit him. He had sent greeting cards to Riaan every year since he had been released from prison. As he grew older, he attached notes requiring him to be disciplined in his studies. When he finished school, he helped him access a professional diving course. “Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility,” Brand said. I don't know any fellows who didn't have any devotion for him, no matter how much experience he had or cynical he was. And in December 2005, another traffic accident. Riaan died at the age of 22. Christo Brand was at the tanatorium identifying his son's body when Mandela called him to offer his condolences and tell him that he wanted to travel there and go to the funeral. “But it was the next day and he couldn't attend,” Brand said, “so as soon as he could, he came to visit me at my house in Cape Town.”. With me he was also kind without need. I wrote him a note the week I was leaving South Africa in early 1995, after six years as a correspondent. I faxed the note and 15 minutes later I got a call from one of his secretaries from the Union Buildings asking me if I could have lunch with the president on Thursday, two days later. I said yes. The secretary told me that this was an occasion on which there would be about fifty people present to celebrate the birthday of an old arms partner of Mandela, Yusuf Cachalia. Then I'd find out through Amina, Cachalia's wife, that Mandela had phoned her before inviting me to ask her if she cared. When his word shift arrived at the meal, he extended in his old friendship with Yusuf Cachalia, but also found time to refer to me cordially a couple of times. Needless to say, I succumbed to your personal charm, but I have the comfort of knowing that I wasn't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened. I don't know any fellow who didn't feel devotion for him, no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was. My friend Bill Keller, who was editor-in-chief of the South African office of the New York Times during my reporting period there, who won a Pulitzer Prize for his work on the fall of the Soviet Union and later became the editor of the Times, once told me in his office that none of the exalted political personalities he had met were equal to Mandela. Zelda la Grange [her personal assistant], who could know much better than us, also said that she had never met anyone comparable to him. He told me that he loved his sense of humor, that no one among all the supposedly great ones was able to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others, “but with grace”. As he said, the best feature of his person was actually very simple: “His humanity. His way of being a great human being. The question that people often ask is whether it is true that he was not resentful, and the answer is very simple: no! He has never shown a slightest hint of it. If I had been in his place, I wouldn't have behaved like this!So he's a special, extraordinary human being. He's very generous, and that's how he cares about normal people. He really wants to know how your father, your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you.”. Zelda said that was the reason I admired him, but it was actually much more than that: I loved him. Love, or something very similar, was also how I felt about him John Reinders. A year after Mandela left the presidency, Reinders, who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor, Thabo Mbeki, received a phone call from his former boss asking him if he and his family could go to his home for lunch the following Sunday. Tears swept through Reinders' cheeks as he told me how he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela's house in Johannesburg. I was hoping to be part of a big meeting, but there was only John, his wife, the boys, and Mandela. “We sat down to eat, but before we started, Mandela got up and raised his glass. He did not address me, but my wife and children. He apologized to them for making me work so hard. He said he had too often deprived them of my company as husband and father. Then he looked at me, looked back at them again and said: ‘But he performed his duties in an excellent way. Excellent!”. After lunch, Mandela accompanied Reinders and his family to the door and escorted them to his car. “He stood there saying goodbye with his hand with that beautiful and huge smile until we walked away. We all greeted him back.”. Why did he invite them to eat and dedicate that speech of gratitude and apology to the wife and children of John Reinders?Because he put into private practice the same values that he promulgated on the public stage; because in the privacy of his home, far from the television cameras, he always behaved in a generous, respectful, kind and courteous manner without any personal or political interest. Mandela's smile, by John Carlin, is already on sale edited by Debate. 192 pages. EUR 15,90. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "elpais.com",
    "date": "06/12/2013",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "He me forgot Reinders' I Mandela well.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that He me forgot Reinders' I Mandela well?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Reinders I Mandela mean?",
                    "score": 0.812,
                    "answers": "Reinders ' I Mandela|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of Reinders I Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.7358,
                    "answers": "I|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Reinders I Mandela and Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.719,
                    "answers": "me|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Reinders I Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6738,
                    "answers": "well|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "me no one among all the supposedly great ones Reinders' no one among all the supposedly great ones his wife and two teenage children Mandela's his Riaan of an old arms partner of Mandela, Yusuf Cachalia me an old arms partner of Mandela, Yusuf Cachalia his son Riaan, whom he held in prison when he was a baby I his son Riaan, whom he held in prison when he was a baby Riaan Reinders' Amina, Cachalia's wife his wife two teenage children his son Riaan, whom he held in prison when he was a baby .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's old arms partner?",
                    "answer": "Yusuf Cachalia"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When was Riaan born?",
                    "score": 0.7693,
                    "answers": "when he was a baby|advcl\twhen he was a baby|advcl\twhen he was a baby|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Riaan Reinders held when he was a baby?",
                    "score": 0.7673,
                    "answers": "Yusuf Cachalia his son Riaan , whom he held in prison when he was a baby I his son Riaan , whom he held in prison when he was a baby Riaan Reinders ' Amina , Cachalia 's wife his wife two teenage children his son Riaan , whom he held in prison when he was a baby|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Mandela and Riaan Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.6735,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tno|det\tall|predet\tthe|det\tsupposedly|advmod\tsupposedly great|amod\t'|case\tno|det\tamong all the supposedly great ones his wife and two teenage children|prep\tall|predet\tthe|det\tsupposedly|advmod\tsupposedly great|amod\tall the supposedly great ones his wife and two teenage children|pobj\tand|cc\tteenage|amod\ttwo teenage children|conj\tan|det\tof Mandela|prep\t,|punct\tan|det\tof Mandela|prep\t,|punct\t,|punct\twhom|dobj\the|nsubj\twhen|advmod\the|nsubj\ta|det\t,|punct\twhom|dobj\the|nsubj\twhen|advmod\the|nsubj\ta|det\t'|case\t,|punct\tteenage|amod\t,|punct\twhom|dobj\the|nsubj\twhen|advmod\the|nsubj\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of Riaan Reinders' husband?",
                    "score": 0.6695,
                    "answers": "I his son Riaan , whom he held in prison when he was a baby|appos\ttwo teenage children his son Riaan , whom he held in prison when he was a baby|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Cachalia and Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6535,
                    "answers": "arms|compound\tarms|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mandela's He We his Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend me Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend Amina, Cachalia's wife Mandela's Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend Mandela Mandela's told me Mandela's me prison Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend always called his wife and two teenage children while Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend called an old arms partner of Mandela, Yusuf Cachalia his wife and two teenage children “NelsonReinders' .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's wife and two teenage children's \"NelsonReinders\"?",
                    "answer": "Yusuf Cachalia"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's me prison partner?",
                    "score": 0.6866,
                    "answers": "Mandela 's me prison Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend always called his wife and two teenage children while Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend called an old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia his wife and two teenage children “ NelsonReinders '|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's friend Brand?",
                    "score": 0.6823,
                    "answers": "'s|case\this|poss\this Brand|appos\tabout Mandela|prep\tother|amod\tme|nmod\tme Brand|appos\tabout Mandela|prep\tother|amod\t's|case\t's|case\tabout Mandela|prep\tother|amod\t's|case\tme|dobj\t's|case\tme|nmod\tprison|compound\tabout Mandela|prep\tother|amod\tany other friend|nsubj\this|poss\this wife and two teenage children|dobj\tabout Mandela|prep\tother|amod\tany other friend|pobj\tof Mandela|prep\tYusuf|compound\this|poss\this wife and|appos\t“|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Mandela's relationship with Brand?",
                    "score": 0.6822,
                    "answers": "who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend me Brand|relcl\talmost like any other friend Amina|prep\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend Mandela Mandela 's|relcl\talmost like any other friend Mandela Mandela 's|prep\tany other friend Mandela Mandela 's|pobj\talmost like any other friend always called his wife and two teenage children|advcl\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|relcl\talmost like any other friend|prep\tarms|compound\t“ NelsonReinders '|oprd"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Brand's relationship with Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6798,
                    "answers": "almost like any other friend me Brand|prep\ta good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend always called his wife and two teenage children while Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend called an old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia his wife and two teenage children “ NelsonReinders '|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Brand say about Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6767,
                    "answers": "He We his Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend me Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend Amina , Cachalia 's wife Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend Mandela Mandela 's|nsubj\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend always called his wife and two teenage children while Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend called an old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia his wife and two teenage children “ NelsonReinders '|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This custom never changed, not Riaan when Mandela his wife and two teenage children his Mandela's presidency and Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend phoned Riaan to Mandela's me .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was the only person who changed the custom when Mandela's wife and two teenage children were under his presidency?",
                    "answer": "Riaan"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Mandela and Riaan Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6808,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that This custom never changed , not Riaan Mandela his wife and when two teenage children his Mandela 's presidency and Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend phoned Riaan to Mandela 's me|ROOT\tthat This custom never changed , not Riaan Mandela his wife and when two teenage children his Mandela 's presidency and Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend phoned Riaan to Mandela 's me|ccomp\tnot Riaan Mandela his wife and when two teenage children his Mandela 's presidency and|npadvmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the practice of calling Mandela a friend?",
                    "score": 0.6769,
                    "answers": "This custom|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mandela me Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend house his , Reinders' detail that Reinders' had with the He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela's they me again Reinders and his family : “Mandela Mandela Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela's Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did elpais.com report that when he mentioned Mandela's they me again?",
                    "answer": "Reinders and his family"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Reinders say about Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.7543,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Mandela me Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend house his , Reinders ' detail that Reinders ' had with the He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Mandela me Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend house his , Reinders ' detail that Reinders ' had with the He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|dobj\t,|punct\ta|det\tgood|amod\t-|punct\tgood - looking|amod\ta good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend house his|appos\twho|nsubj\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend house his|relcl\talmost|advmod\talmost like any other friend house his|prep\tany|det\tother|amod\tany other friend house his|pobj\thouse his|prep\this|case\t,|punct\tReinders '|poss\t'|case\tthat|dobj\tReinders '|nsubj\t'|case\tthat Reinders ' had with the He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|relcl\twith the He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|prep\tthe|det\tHe|nmod\tthe He naturalness that when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|pobj\tthat when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family|nmod\twhen|advmod\tHe|nsubj\twhen He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family|prep\tMandela 's they me again Reinders and his family|dobj\t's|case\tthey|dep\tme again|nmod\tagain|advmod\tthey me again Reinders and his family|appos\tand|cc\this|poss\this family|conj\t:|punct\t“|punct\tthat when He mentioned Mandela 's they me again Reinders and his family : “ Mandela Mandela Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs ”|acl\t,|punct\ta|det\tgood|amod\t-|punct\tgood - looking|amod\ta good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand|appos\twho|nsubj\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand|relcl\talmost|advmod\talmost like any other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand|prep\tany|det\tother|amod\tany other friend to the Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand|pobj\tthe|det\tthe Reinders and his family of Mandela 's Brand|pobj\tand|cc\this|poss\this family of Mandela 's Brand|conj\tof Mandela 's Brand|prep\tMandela 's|poss\t's|case\tMandela 's Brand|pobj\t,|punct\ta|det\tgood|amod\t-|punct\tgood - looking|amod\ta good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs|appos\twho|nsubj\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs|relcl\talmost|advmod\tlike|mark\tany|det\tother|amod\tany other friend|nsubj\talmost like any other friend helped He climb the stairs|advcl\tHe|nsubj\tHe climb the stairs|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe stairs|dobj\t”|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Mandela Brand's relationship with Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.7443,
                    "answers": "about Mandela|prep\tabout Mandela|prep\tabout Mandela|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Mandela Brand and Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.6902,
                    "answers": "me|nmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mandela's invited Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to He 80th birthday me his the New York Times in I in 1998, an me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife, the his wife and two teenage children Reinders, who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor, Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela's of his Machel, and former Minister Mandela Mandela's He Zelda la Grange [her personal assistant], who could know much better than us .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on Mandela's invitation of Brand?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was He Zelda la Grange?",
                    "answer": "who could know much better than us"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did Mandela invite to his 80th birthday?",
                    "score": 0.7339,
                    "answers": "that Mandela 's invited Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend to He 80th birthday me his the New York Times in I in 1998 , an me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's third wife?",
                    "score": 0.6316,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tMandela 's|nsubj\t's|case\t,|punct\ta|det\t-|punct\twho|nsubj\tabout Mandela|prep\talmost like any other friend|prep\tany|det\tother|amod\tany other friend|pobj\tto He 80th birthday me his the New York Times in I in 1998 , an me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|prep\tHe|nmod\tHe 80th birthday me his the New York Times in I in 1998 , an me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|pobj\tme his the New York Times in I in 1998 , an me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|appos\this|dep\tthe|det\tNew|compound\tNew York|compound\this the New York Times|appos\tin I|prep\tI|pobj\tin 1998|prep\t,|punct\tme|nmod\tan me Reinders and his family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|appos\tand|cc\this|poss\this family which his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|conj\twhich|dep\this|nmod\tme|dep\tthe|det\this|nmod\this|poss\twhich his me the his his third wife , the his wife and two teenage children Reinders ,|relcl\t,|punct\tthe|det\this|poss\tthe his wife and two teenage children Reinders ,|conj\tand|cc\tReinders ,|appos\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tin the Cabinet|prep\tthe|det\tthe Cabinet|pobj\this|poss\t,|punct\tThabo|compound\tThabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel|appos\tof whom|prep\twhom|pobj\tof whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel|relcl\tMandela 's of his Machel|attr\t's|case\tof his Machel|prep\this|poss\this Machel|pobj\t,|punct\tand|cc\tformer|amod\tformer Minister|compound\tformer Minister Mandela Mandela 's|poss\t's|case\tHe|compound\tZelda|compound\tla|compound\t[|punct\ther|poss\tpersonal|amod\t]|punct\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tmuch|advmod\tthan us|prep\tus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.6279,
                    "answers": "who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|relcl\tformer Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|conj\ther personal assistant|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Mandela and Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6169,
                    "answers": "serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|advcl\this successor , Thabo Mbeki of whom Mandela was Mandela 's of his Machel , and former Minister Mandela Mandela 's He Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4984,
                    "answers": "elpais.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Zelda la Grange [her personal assistant], who could know much better than us .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that Zelda la Grange was her personal assistant?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com report about Zelda la Grange?",
                    "answer": "[her personal assistant], who could know much better than us"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is Zelda la Grange's personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.7363,
                    "answers": "Zelda|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Zelda La Grange's personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.7363,
                    "answers": "that Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the personal assistant of Zelda la Grange?",
                    "score": 0.7314,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tla|compound\t[|punct\ther|poss\t]|punct\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the personal assistant to Zelda la Grange?",
                    "score": 0.6867,
                    "answers": "her personal assistant|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Zelda la Grange and her personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.6834,
                    "answers": "could|aux\twho could know much better than us|relcl\tmuch|advmod\tmuch better than us|advmod\tthan us|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It was the first Zelda la Grange [her personal assistant], who could know much better than us in life that Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend got on a plane.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Zelda la Grange was the first personal assistant?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did Brand talk about like any other friend?",
                    "answer": "Mandela"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was Brand's relationship with Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6311,
                    "answers": "who could know much better than us in life that Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend got on a plane|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the first friend to meet Mandela on a plane?",
                    "score": 0.6275,
                    "answers": "Zelda|compound\tla|compound\ther|poss\ta plane|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.6006,
                    "answers": "personal|amod\tabout Mandela|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Brand and Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.5703,
                    "answers": "that It was the first Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us in life that Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend got on a plane|ccomp\tcould|aux\tlife|pobj\ta|det\twho talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|relcl\tlike|mark\tthat Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend got on a plane|ccomp\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the personal assistant to Zelda la Grange?",
                    "score": 0.5554,
                    "answers": "her personal assistant|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mandela years later it would be Mandela who would fly to city to visit Brand, a good-looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela do to visit Brand?",
                    "answer": "fly to city to visit Brand,"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Mandela meet Brand?",
                    "score": 0.8273,
                    "answers": "city|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela say about Brand Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.8266,
                    "answers": "good - looking|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Mandela's relationship with Brand?",
                    "score": 0.7111,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Mandela years later it would be Mandela who would fly to city to visit Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|ROOT\tthat Mandela years later it would be Mandela who would fly to city to visit Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|ccomp\tabout Mandela|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Mandela's friend?",
                    "score": 0.6745,
                    "answers": "any|det\tother|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Mandela and Brand?",
                    "score": 0.6543,
                    "answers": "who would fly to city to visit Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|ccomp\tto visit Brand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|advcl\tBrand , a good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|dobj\ta good - looking man who talked about Mandela almost like any other friend|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He had sent greeting cards to Riaan every year since he had been released from prison.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that he had sent greeting cards to Riaan?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many greeting cards were sent to Riaan every year since he was released from prison?",
                    "score": 0.6783,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that He had sent greeting cards to Riaan every year since he had been released from prison|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tHe|nsubj\thad|aux\tthat He had sent greeting cards to Riaan every year since he had been released from prison|ccomp\tgreeting|compound\tgreeting cards|dobj\tto Riaan|dative\tevery|det\tevery year since he had been released from prison|npadvmod\tsince|mark\the|nsubjpass\thad|aux\tbeen|auxpass\tsince he had been released from prison|advcl\tfrom prison|prep\tprison|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "As he grew older, he attached notes requiring him to be disciplined in his studies.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that he attached notes requiring him to be disciplined in his studies as he grew older?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the notes require him to be disciplined in his studies?",
                    "score": 0.713,
                    "answers": "notes requiring him to be disciplined in his studies|dobj\trequiring him to be disciplined in his studies|acl\tbe|auxpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Scott Walker being disciplined as he grew older?",
                    "score": 0.6647,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many notes did he attach to his studies as a child?",
                    "score": 0.6343,
                    "answers": "him|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between being disciplined and being a student?",
                    "score": 0.6016,
                    "answers": "in his studies|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the age gap between being older and being older?",
                    "score": 0.5459,
                    "answers": "older|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "When he finished school, he helped him access a professional diving course.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that he helped him access a professional diving course?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many professional diving courses did Scott Walker receive after he finished school?",
                    "score": 0.8351,
                    "answers": "When he finished school|advcl\ta professional diving course|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that the author of the article was able to access a professional diving course?",
                    "score": 0.7884,
                    "answers": "him access a professional diving course|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.6038,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tWhen|advmod\the|nsubj\tschool|dobj\t,|punct\the|nsubj\ta|det\tprofessional|amod\tdiving|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility,” Brand said.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that \"Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility\"?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela say about Riaan?",
                    "score": 0.8362,
                    "answers": "that “ Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility|ccomp\tthat I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility|ccomp\tRiaan to be my own responsibility|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela tell Brand about her own responsibility?",
                    "score": 0.8212,
                    "answers": "my own responsibility|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Mandela and Riaan?",
                    "score": 0.6968,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that “ Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility|ccomp\telpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that “ Mandela always told me that I considered Riaan to be my own responsibility , ” Brand said|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I don't know any fellows who didn't have any devotion for him, no matter how much experience he had or cynical he was.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that I didn't know any fellows who didn't have any devotion for him?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the affiliation of the fellows who didn't have any devotion for him?",
                    "score": 0.7169,
                    "answers": "n't|neg\tn't|neg\thow much|amod\thow much experience|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a fellow and a fellow?",
                    "score": 0.5788,
                    "answers": "for him|prep\thim|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4865,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that I do n't know any fellows who did n't have any devotion for him , no matter how much experience he had or cynical he was|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tI|nsubj\tdo|aux\t,|punct\tno matter how much experience he had or cynical he was|advmod\thow|advmod\the|nsubj\tor|cc\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And in December 2005, another traffic accident.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that a traffic accident happened in December 2005?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the traffic accident in 2005?",
                    "score": 0.6444,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tAnd|cc\tin December 2005 ,|prep\t2005|nummod\t,|punct\tanother|det\ttraffic|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4807,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that And in December 2005 , another traffic accident|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Riaan died at the age of 22.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Riaan died on 06/12/2013?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Riaan die?",
                    "score": 0.852,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Riaan died at the age of 22|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tthat Riaan died at the age of 22|ccomp\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was Riaan when she died?",
                    "score": 0.8115,
                    "answers": "at the age of 22|prep\tof 22|prep\t22|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Christo Brand was at the tanatorium identifying his son's body when Mandela called him to offer his condolences and tell him that he wanted to travel there and go to the funeral.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Christo Brand was at the tanatorium identifying his son's body when Mandela called him to offer his condolences?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Brand say to Mandela about his son's body?",
                    "score": 0.7814,
                    "answers": "to|aux\tto|aux\tto the funeral|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Christo Brand when Mandela called him to deliver his condolences?",
                    "score": 0.7476,
                    "answers": "the|det\twhen|advmod\tand|cc\the|nsubj\tthere|advmod\tand|cc\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of Christo Brand's son's body?",
                    "score": 0.6163,
                    "answers": "that|mark\this|poss\this son 's body|dobj\this|poss\tthat|mark"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the body of Christo Brand?",
                    "score": 0.5935,
                    "answers": "his son 's|poss\thim|dobj\thim|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“But it was the next day and he couldn't attend,” Brand said, “so as soon as he could, he came to visit me at my house in Cape Town.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that Brand couldn't attend?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was Brand's house in Cape Town in 2013?",
                    "score": 0.5965,
                    "answers": "my house in Cape Town|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of Brand's visit to Cape Town?",
                    "score": 0.5708,
                    "answers": "“|punct\tn't|neg\t”|punct\t, ” Brand said ,|parataxis\t“|punct\tas he could|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What day was the next day in Cape Town?",
                    "score": 0.5651,
                    "answers": "it was the next day and he could n't attend|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that Brand is a part of?",
                    "score": 0.4763,
                    "answers": "Cape|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "With me he was also kind without need.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 06/12/2013 that With me he was also kind?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about him?",
                    "score": 0.6548,
                    "answers": "he|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com do?",
                    "score": 0.5934,
                    "answers": "that|mark\talso|advmod\tneed|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between elpais.com and him?",
                    "score": 0.5295,
                    "answers": "that With me he was also kind without need|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I wrote him a note the week I was leaving South Africa in early 1995, after six years as a correspondent.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that I wrote him a note the week I was leaving South Africa?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elpais.com write him a note the week he was leaving South Africa?",
                    "score": 0.6743,
                    "answers": "that I wrote him a note the week I was leaving South Africa in early 1995 , after six years as a correspondent|ccomp\tthe week I was leaving South Africa in early 1995 , after six years as a correspondent|npadvmod\tI was leaving South Africa in early 1995 , after six years as a correspondent|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the first note from South Africa's foreign minister?",
                    "score": 0.611,
                    "answers": "early|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a correspondent and a correspondent in South Africa?",
                    "score": 0.558,
                    "answers": "a correspondent|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I faxed the note and 15 minutes later I got a call from one of his secretaries from the Union Buildings asking me if I could have lunch with the president on Thursday, two days later.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the secretary of the Union Buildings say to the president on Thursday?",
                    "score": 0.6556,
                    "answers": "15 minutes later I got a call from one of his secretaries from the Union Buildings asking me if I could have lunch with the president on Thursday , two days later|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the letter from the secretary from the Union Buildings?",
                    "score": 0.5751,
                    "answers": "Thursday , two days later|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the president's secretary?",
                    "score": 0.5397,
                    "answers": "one of his secretaries|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the president?",
                    "score": 0.5276,
                    "answers": "the president|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the president and elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4615,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that I faxed the note and 15 minutes later I got a call from one of his secretaries from the Union Buildings asking me if I could have lunch with the president on Thursday , two days later|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tI|nsubj\tthe|det\tand|cc\t15|nummod\tI|nsubj\ta|det\this|poss\tfrom the Union Buildings|prep\tthe|det\tme|dobj\tif|mark\tI|nsubj\tcould|aux\tif I could have lunch with the president on Thursday , two days later|ccomp\tlunch with the president|dobj\twith the president|prep\tthe|det\t,|punct\ttwo|nummod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The secretary told me that this was an occasion on which there would be about fifty people present to celebrate the birthday of an old arms partner of Mandela, Yusuf Cachalia.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people were there to celebrate the birthday of Yusuf Cachalia?",
                    "answer": "fifty"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people attended the birthday of an old arms partner of Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6494,
                    "answers": "about fifty people present to celebrate the birthday of an old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Mandela and Cachalia?",
                    "score": 0.5279,
                    "answers": "of an old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia|prep\tan old arms partner of Mandela , Yusuf Cachalia|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Then I'd find out through Amina, Cachalia's wife, that Mandela had phoned her before inviting me to ask her if she cared.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Mandela had phoned Cachalia's wife before inviting me to ask her if she cared?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did Mandela invite to ask if she cared?",
                    "score": 0.7074,
                    "answers": "her|dobj\ther|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Mandela and Cachalia?",
                    "score": 0.5802,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Then I 'd find out through Amina , Cachalia 's wife , that Mandela had phoned her before inviting me to ask her if she cared|ROOT\tthat Then I 'd find out through Amina , Cachalia 's wife , that Mandela had phoned her before inviting me to ask her if she cared|ccomp\tthat Mandela had phoned her before inviting me to ask her if she cared|ccomp\tme|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Cachalia's wife?",
                    "score": 0.5114,
                    "answers": "through Amina , Cachalia 's wife ,|prep\tAmina , Cachalia 's wife ,|pobj\tCachalia 's wife|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Cachalia's husband?",
                    "score": 0.5049,
                    "answers": "Cachalia 's|poss"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "When his word shift arrived at the meal, he extended in his old friendship with Yusuf Cachalia, but also found time to refer to me cordially a couple of times.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that he extended his old friendship with Yusuf Cachalia?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the word shift at a meal?",
                    "score": 0.482,
                    "answers": "his word shift|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Yusuf Cachalia and Mark Twain?",
                    "score": 0.4786,
                    "answers": "with Yusuf Cachalia|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Mark Twain and Yusuf Cachalia?",
                    "score": 0.4669,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tWhen|advmod\this|poss\tthe|det\t,|punct\this|poss\t,|punct\tbut|cc\talso|advmod\talso found time to refer to me cordially a couple of times|conj\ttime to refer to me cordially a couple of times|dobj\tto|aux\tto refer to me cordially a couple of times|relcl\tto me|prep\tme|pobj\ta|det\tof times|prep\ttimes|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the meal?",
                    "score": 0.4412,
                    "answers": "the meal|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man who spoke during the meal?",
                    "score": 0.425,
                    "answers": "When his word shift arrived at the meal|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Needless to say, I succumbed to your personal charm, but I have the comfort of knowing that I wasn't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that I succumbed to your personal charm?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the only journalist to know that the same thing happened to the same journalist?",
                    "score": 0.5747,
                    "answers": "the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a journalist and a journalist?",
                    "score": 0.5443,
                    "answers": "I have the comfort of knowing that I was n't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|conj\tthe comfort of knowing that I was n't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|dobj\tof knowing that I was n't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|prep\tknowing that I was n't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between elpais.com and the tabloid?",
                    "score": 0.5187,
                    "answers": "that Needless to say , I succumbed to your personal charm , but I have the comfort of knowing that I was n't the only one of the journalists to whom the same thing happened|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the relationship between news organizations like elpais.com and the website?",
                    "score": 0.5015,
                    "answers": "to say|xcomp\tn't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4441,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tto|aux\t,|punct\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tthe|det\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthe|det\tthe|det\tsame|amod\tthe same thing|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I don't know any fellow who didn't feel devotion for him, no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 06/12/2013 that I didn't know a fellow who didn't feel devotion for him?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about a fellow who didn't feel devotion for him?",
                    "score": 0.6089,
                    "answers": "any fellow who did n't feel devotion for him , no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was|dobj\twho did n't feel devotion for him , no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a fellow and a fellow?",
                    "score": 0.5107,
                    "answers": "that I do n't know any fellow who did n't feel devotion for him , no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4425,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that I do n't know any fellow who did n't feel devotion for him , no matter how experienced he was or cynical he was|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tI|nsubj\tdo|aux\thim|pobj\t,|punct\thow|advmod\thow experienced he was or cynical he was|ccomp\tor|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "My friend Bill Keller, who was editor-in-chief of the South African office of the New York Times during my reporting period there, who won a Pulitzer Prize for his work on the fall of the Soviet Union and later became the editor of the Times, once told me in his office that none of the exalted political personalities he had met were equal to Mandela.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Bill Keller once told me that none of the exalted political personalities he had met were equal to Mandela?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What political figures did Bill Keller meet?",
                    "score": 0.8145,
                    "answers": "none of the exalted political personalities he had met|nsubj\tthe exalted political personalities he had met|pobj\the had met|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What award did Bill Keller win for his work on the fall of the Soviet Union?",
                    "score": 0.8126,
                    "answers": "Pulitzer|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Bill Keller do to become the editor of the New York Times?",
                    "score": 0.7329,
                    "answers": "later became the editor of the Times|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Bill Keller's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.6921,
                    "answers": "political|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Bill Keller's history with the Soviet Union?",
                    "score": 0.6364,
                    "answers": "who won a Pulitzer Prize for his work on the fall of the Soviet Union and later became the editor of the Times|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Zelda la Grange [her personal assistant], who could know much better than us, also said that she had never met anyone comparable to him.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Zelda la Grange had never met anyone comparable to him?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did Zelda la Grange know better than us?",
                    "score": 0.7338,
                    "answers": "who could know much better than us|relcl\tthan us|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Zelda La Grange's personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.6904,
                    "answers": "Zelda la Grange [ her personal assistant ] , who could know much better than us ,|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the personal assistant of Zelda la Grange?",
                    "score": 0.6586,
                    "answers": "Zelda|compound\tla|compound\ther|poss\tshe|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Zelda la Grange and her personal assistant?",
                    "score": 0.6496,
                    "answers": "personal|amod\tcould|aux\tmuch|advmod\thad|aux\tnever|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the personal assistant to Zelda la Grange?",
                    "score": 0.6438,
                    "answers": "her personal assistant|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He told me that he loved his sense of humor, that no one among all the supposedly great ones was able to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others, “but with grace”.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Mandela told me that he loved his sense of humor?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela say about his sense of humor?",
                    "score": 0.7976,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that He told me that he loved his sense of humor , that no one among all the supposedly great ones was able to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others , “ but with grace ”|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tHe|nsubj\tthat He told me that he loved his sense of humor , that no one among all the supposedly great ones was able to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others , “ but with grace ”|ccomp\tme|dobj\tthat|mark\the|nsubj\tthat he loved his sense of humor|advcl\this|poss\tof humor|prep\t,|punct\tthat|mark\tno|det\tno one among all the supposedly great ones|nsubj\tall|predet\tthe|det\tsupposedly|advmod\tsupposedly great|amod\tall the supposedly great ones|pobj\tthat he loved his sense of humor , that no one among all the supposedly great ones was able to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others , “ but with grace ”|advcl\table to laugh at himself as Mandela did before others , “ but with grace|acomp\tto|aux\tto laugh at himself as Mandela did before others , “ but with grace|xcomp\tat himself|prep\thimself|pobj\tas|mark\tbefore others|prep\tothers|pobj\t,|punct\t“|punct\tbut|cc\t“ but with grace|prep\tgrace|pobj\t”|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Mandela's sense of humor?",
                    "score": 0.6623,
                    "answers": "his sense of humor|dobj\tamong all the supposedly great ones|prep\tas Mandela did before others|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "As he said, the best feature of his person was actually very simple: “His humanity.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on the 06/12/2013 that he said that the best feature of his person was his humanity?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the best feature of a person's humanity?",
                    "score": 0.6524,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tAs|mark\the|nsubj\tAs he said|advcl\t,|punct\tthe|det\tbest|amod\tof his person|prep\this|poss\this person|pobj\tthat As he said , the best feature of his person was actually very simple : “ His humanity|ccomp\tactually|advmod\tvery|advmod\tvery simple|attr\t:|punct\t“|punct\tHis|poss\tHis humanity|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4776,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that As he said , the best feature of his person was actually very simple : “ His humanity|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "His way of being a great human being.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on Jesus' way of being a great human being on 06/12/2013?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about human?",
                    "score": 0.6881,
                    "answers": "human|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4902,
                    "answers": "a|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The question that people often ask is whether it is true that he was not resentful, and the answer is very simple: no! He has never shown a slightest hint of it.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that he was not resentful?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How does he feel about being resentful?",
                    "answer": "He has never shown a slightest hint of it"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about whether or not he was resentful?",
                    "score": 0.6456,
                    "answers": "whether|mark\tit|nsubj\tnot|neg\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthe|det\tthe answer|nsubj\tthe answer is very simple : no|conj\tvery|advmod\tvery simple|acomp\t:|punct\tno|intj\t!|punct\ta|det\tit|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the question that people often ask about whether it is true that he was not resentful?",
                    "score": 0.6198,
                    "answers": "that The question that people often ask is whether it is true that he was not resentful , and the answer is very simple : no|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the evidence of Gary Johnson's feelings towards his father?",
                    "score": 0.5985,
                    "answers": "of it|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between resentful and resentful?",
                    "score": 0.5926,
                    "answers": "that he was not resentful|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Clemon Brown's feelings on hate crimes?",
                    "score": 0.5858,
                    "answers": "that people often ask|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "If I had been in his place, I wouldn't have behaved like this!So he's a special, extraordinary human being.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 06/12/2013 that if I had been in his place, I wouldn't have behaved like this?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about a human being?",
                    "score": 0.5914,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tIf|mark\tI|nsubj\this place|pobj\t,|punct\tI|nsubj\twould|aux\thave|aux\tlike|prep\the|nsubj\tspecial|amod\t,|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a human being and a criminal?",
                    "score": 0.4648,
                    "answers": "had|aux\this|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4298,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that If I had been in his place , I would n't have behaved like this!So he 's a special , extraordinary human being|ROOT\tIf I had been in his place|advcl\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He's very generous, and that's how he cares about normal people.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that he's very generous?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to be generous?",
                    "score": 0.8175,
                    "answers": "very generous|acomp\tnormal people|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about normal people?",
                    "score": 0.7233,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that He 's very generous , and that 's how he cares about normal people|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tHe|nsubj\tthat He 's very generous , and that 's how he cares about normal people|ccomp\tvery|advmod\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthat|nsubj\thow|advmod\the|nsubj\tabout normal people|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the difference between normal people and normal people?",
                    "score": 0.6053,
                    "answers": "normal|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He really wants to know how your father, your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that he really wants to know how your father, your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you questions?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a father and a brother?",
                    "score": 0.5778,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tHe|nsubj\tthat He really wants to know how your father , your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you|ccomp\tto know how your father , your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you|xcomp\the|nsubj\twhen he asks you|advcl\tyou|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com do?",
                    "score": 0.5522,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that He really wants to know how your father , your mother or your brother is doing when he asks you|ROOT\tthat|mark\treally|advmod\tto|aux\t,|punct\tor|cc\tis|aux\twhen|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Zelda said that was the reason I admired him, but it was actually much more than that: I loved him.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Zelda said that was the reason I admired him?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Zelda and Link?",
                    "score": 0.7033,
                    "answers": "the reason I admired him|attr\tI admired him|relcl\tmuch more than that|acomp\t: I loved him|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about him?",
                    "score": 0.6398,
                    "answers": "that was the reason I admired him , but it was actually much more than that|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.5164,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Zelda said that was the reason I admired him , but it was actually much more than that : I loved him|ROOT\tthat|mark\tthat|nsubj\tthe|det\tI|nsubj\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tit|nsubj\tactually|advmod\tthat|pobj\t:|punct\tI|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Love, or something very similar, was also how I felt about him John Reinders.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Love was also how I felt about John Reinders?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between John Reinders and Love?",
                    "score": 0.6665,
                    "answers": "how I felt about him|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Love and John Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.6307,
                    "answers": "something very similar ,|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com say about John Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.6251,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Love , or something very similar , was also how I felt about him John Reinders|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A year after Mandela left the presidency, Reinders, who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor, Thabo Mbeki, received a phone call from his former boss asking him if he and his family could go to his home for lunch the following Sunday.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Thabo Mbeki's family want to go to his home for?",
                    "answer": "lunch"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Reinders get a phone call from Thabo Mbeki?",
                    "score": 0.7792,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tA|det\tafter|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tthe|det\this|poss\t,|punct\t,|punct\ta|det\tphone|compound\tfrom his former boss|prep\this|poss\tformer|amod\thim|dobj\tif|mark\the and his family|nsubj\tand|cc\this|poss\tcould|aux\tto his home|prep\this|poss\tfor lunch|prep\tlunch|pobj\tthe|det\tfollowing|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Reinders and Thabo Mbeki?",
                    "score": 0.5307,
                    "answers": "the presidency|dobj\tReinders , who continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki ,|nsubj\twho continued in the Cabinet serving his successor , Thabo Mbeki ,|relcl\tthe Cabinet|pobj\tserving his successor , Thabo Mbeki ,|advcl\this successor , Thabo Mbeki ,|dobj\tThabo|compound\this former boss|pobj\this family|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Tears swept through Reinders' cheeks as he told me how he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela's house in Johannesburg.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that tears swept through Reinders' cheeks on 06/12/2013?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Reinders meet Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.7392,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Tears swept through Reinders ' cheeks as he told me how he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela 's house in Johannesburg|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat Tears swept through Reinders ' cheeks as he told me how he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela 's house in Johannesburg|ccomp\tas he told me how he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela 's house in Johannesburg|advcl\thow he presented himself with his wife and two teenage children at Mandela 's house in Johannesburg|ccomp\twith his wife and two teenage children|prep\tand|cc\tat Mandela 's house in Johannesburg|prep\t's|case"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Mandela's house in Johannesburg?",
                    "score": 0.6701,
                    "answers": "his|poss\tMandela 's|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Reinders say about Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.669,
                    "answers": "Reinders '|poss\tReinders ' cheeks|pobj\the|nsubj\the|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Reinders when he presented himself to Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.6449,
                    "answers": "his wife and two teenage children|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Reinders and Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.5323,
                    "answers": "teenage|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I was hoping to be part of a big meeting, but there was only John, his wife, the boys, and Mandela.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that I was hoping to be part of a big meeting?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who attended the meeting with Mandela?",
                    "score": 0.7336,
                    "answers": "only John , his wife , the boys , and Mandela|attr\tthe boys , and Mandela|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“We sat down to eat, but before we started, Mandela got up and raised his glass.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Mandela got up and raised his glass before we started?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Mandela get up and raise his glass?",
                    "score": 0.7618,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tthat “ We sat down to eat , but before we started , Mandela got up and raised his glass|ccomp\tto eat|advcl\tbefore we started|advcl\tbefore we started , Mandela got up and raised his glass|conj\tup|prt"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela do to raise his glass?",
                    "score": 0.6917,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that “ We sat down to eat , but before we started , Mandela got up and raised his glass|ROOT\tthat|mark\tWe|nsubj\tdown|prt\tto|aux\tbut|cc\tbefore|mark\twe|nsubj\traised his glass|conj\this|poss\this glass|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He did not address me, but my wife and children.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that He did not address me?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about Trump?",
                    "score": 0.8176,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that He did not address me , but my wife and children|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Trump and his wife and children?",
                    "score": 0.6889,
                    "answers": "children|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the website \"lpais.com\" say about the claims?",
                    "score": 0.6651,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep\tdid|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the person that was identified by the website?",
                    "score": 0.6125,
                    "answers": "but|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He said he had too often deprived them of my company as husband and father.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 06/12/2013 that he had too often deprived them of my company as husband and father?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a husband and father?",
                    "score": 0.4563,
                    "answers": "too often|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Scott Walker and Elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4521,
                    "answers": "he had too often deprived them of my company as husband and father|ccomp\tof my company|prep\tmy company|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that posted the claims?",
                    "score": 0.4154,
                    "answers": "on 06/12/2013|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Then he looked at me, looked back at them again and said: ‘But he performed his duties in an excellent way.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 06/12/2013 that Then he looked at me, looked back at them again and said: 'But he performed his duties in an excellent way'?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did elpais.com say about him?",
                    "score": 0.535,
                    "answers": "said : ‘ But he performed his duties in an excellent way|conj\tBut he performed his duties in an excellent way|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does elpais.com do?",
                    "score": 0.5228,
                    "answers": "back|advmod\texcellent|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that the author of the article was quoted as saying he performed his duties in an excellent way?",
                    "score": 0.5199,
                    "answers": "Then|advmod\t‘|punct\tan excellent way|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the story from the website?",
                    "score": 0.4426,
                    "answers": ",|punct\tand|cc\tBut|cc\this|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4406,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that Then he looked at me , looked back at them again and said : ‘ But he performed his duties in an excellent way|ROOT\tthat|mark\tthem|pobj\t:|punct\tan|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "After lunch, Mandela accompanied Reinders and his family to the door and escorted them to his car.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Mandela accompanied Reinders and his family to the door and escorted them to his car?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was Mandela when he escorted Reinders and his family to his car?",
                    "score": 0.6524,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that After lunch , Mandela accompanied Reinders and his family to the door and escorted them to his car|ROOT\tthat After lunch , Mandela accompanied Reinders and his family to the door and escorted them to his car|ccomp\this|poss\tto the door|prep\tthe door|pobj\tto his car|prep\this|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Mandela do to greet Reinders and his family?",
                    "score": 0.6407,
                    "answers": "Reinders and his family|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“He stood there saying goodbye with his hand with that beautiful and huge smile until we walked away.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that \"He stood there saying goodbye with his hand with that beautiful and huge smile until we walked away?\"",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long did it take for him to walk away?",
                    "score": 0.4886,
                    "answers": "until we walked away|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the date of the wedding?",
                    "score": 0.4737,
                    "answers": "there|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that posted the photo of him saying goodbye with his hand?",
                    "score": 0.4329,
                    "answers": "with that beautiful and huge smile|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the person who said goodbye with his hand with the beautiful and huge smile?",
                    "score": 0.3998,
                    "answers": "away|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Why did he invite them to eat and dedicate that speech of gratitude and apology to the wife and children of John Reinders?Because he put into private practice the same values that he promulgated on the public stage; because in the privacy of his home, far from the television cameras, he always behaved in a generous, respectful, kind and courteous manner without any personal or political interest.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that he invited the wife and children to eat and dedicate his speech of gratitude and apology to the wife and children of John Reinders?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did John Reinders invite to eat and dedicate that speech of gratitude and apology to?",
                    "score": 0.7261,
                    "answers": "to the wife and children of|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What values did John Reinders put into practice on the public stage?",
                    "score": 0.7024,
                    "answers": "the same values that he promulgated on the public stage|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did John Reinders do to the wife and children of Jacob Reinders?",
                    "score": 0.6694,
                    "answers": "to eat|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the speech that John Reinders gave to his wife and children?",
                    "score": 0.5854,
                    "answers": "that speech of gratitude and apology|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between John Reinders and Barack Obama?",
                    "score": 0.5739,
                    "answers": "far from the television cameras|advmod\tpersonal or political|amod\tany personal or political interest|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mandela's smile, by John Carlin, is already on sale edited by Debate.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Mandela's smile was already on sale?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Carlin say about Mandela's smile?",
                    "score": 0.8045,
                    "answers": "John|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is John Carlin?",
                    "score": 0.6158,
                    "answers": "by John Carlin|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "192 pages.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many pages did elpais.com report on 06/12/2013?",
                    "answer": "192"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many pages long is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.6214,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that 192 pages|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark\tthat 192 pages|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "EUR 15,90.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 06/12/2013 that EUR 15,90 was spent?",
                    "answer": "elpais.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the amount of money that the website received in 2013?",
                    "score": 0.5905,
                    "answers": "that EUR 15,90|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elpais.com?",
                    "score": 0.4705,
                    "answers": "elpais.com reported on 06/12/2013 that EUR 15,90|ROOT\ton 06/12/2013|prep\tthat|mark"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}